It's a very great day for Me to see so many Sahaja Yogis here
很高興在希臘這個國家
who are from this country, Greece.
看見這麼多霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
When first I came to Greece,
第一次到來時，
I told My husband that this country is full of vibrations
我告訴丈夫這國家充滿了能量，
and there have been many evolved souls in this country
且有很多進化得很高的靈。
but perhaps the people have lost their heritage,
也許人民已遺失了他們的文化遺產，
but the vibrations are in the atmosphere
但其能量仍存在於大氣之中，
and one day Sahaja Yoga should prosper here very much.
有一天霎哈嘉瑜伽將在此大大昌盛起來。
And somehow, we met some bureaucrats who were Greeks and
那年我們遇上一些希臘官僚，
the experience was not good with them and My husband said
感到不太愉快。我丈夫說：
that, "If you said that Greeks are really religious people,
「若你說希臘人真的是虔誠的民族，
then look at these people - what are they doing to me?"
且看看這些人。他們是怎樣待我呢？」
I said, "They may be bureaucrats and all over, bureaucrats,
我卻說：「雖然有些人很官僚化，普遍是官僚作風的，
you can't say what sort of people they could be."
你不能說他們到底會是怎樣的人。
But, on the whole, the vibrations were very, very good, no doubt,
但整體來說，這裡的能量非常非常好，是毫無疑問的。」
and I went to all the places in here, like I went to Delphi,
我在這個國家曾四處遊歷，去過德爾斐(Delphi)等地，
I went up there to see Athena's temple and everything.
及那兒的雅典娜(Athena)神廟等每一處。
To all the places of interest, they took Me round, especially Me,
人們特意帶我到各處名勝遊覽參觀，
because he was busy with his conference,
因為我丈夫忙於開會。
and so they took Me round. And everywhere I felt
我感到每一處都是如此美麗，
even the sea I felt was so beautiful. This was about,
就連海洋都是這樣美。
I think I came here at least about fifteen years back,
我想那是十四、五年前的事吧。
maybe fourteen years back - and I find now
現在，我發覺那能量
the vibrations are coming back now through you people
藉著你們而復興起來了，
and the whole place is again vibrating.
整個大地都重新充滿了能量。
Now, you have to understand that you people
你們必須明白
have a very big responsibility because you're
你們都肩負著非常大的重任，
strategically placed in Greece, you see.
因為希臘地處要塞，要知道，
Creece and Italy, I mean Turkey, both are very important.
希臘與義大利，我意思是土耳其，兩者是何等重要。
First of all, you are the bridge between the eastern side
首先，你們是東方和西方之間的橋樑。
and the western side and everybody is interested in,
所有人都在打主意，
somehow or another, managing these two areas
因為如果能夠管控這兩個地區
so that hey could control eastern and western side.
就可以操控東西兩邊。
I mean the western countries especially.
我是指尤其對西方國家而言。
Now the greatest danger that you have now
現在你們最大的危險是，
is that this western culture may try to grab you
這些西方文化會嘗試抓住你們，
and which is very dangerous.
那是十分危險的。
To understand it, you have to know
要明白這點，你先要知道
that you are people coming from a very great tradition,
你們像印度人一樣發源自非常偉大的傳統，
ancient people of ages just like Indians,
是遠古的民族；
and there is so much you can do to improve the culture of Europe
而且你們可以做許多事情，
by your own behavior.
可以身作則來改善歐洲文化。
Like these people we have coming here, tourists are coming,
像這些人一樣，我們來到這裡。遊客們到來，
and they see the behavior of the Greeks
他們看到希臘人的舉止，
and they see that they can influence very well,
認為可以很大程度地影響他們
the Europeans, think that Greeks can be very easily influenced
這些歐洲人認為希臘人很容易受到
by their culture, by their cheap life.
他們的文化和低俗的生活方式的影響。
So, as you being the such traditional people,
作為腳踏實地的傳統民族，
down to earth and so many, so many
你們曾從生命中知道了
good things you have known in life,
許許多多的美好事物。
it's very important to understand the historical
故此，首先應瞭解你們
background of your country, first of all.
國家的歷史背景知識，這是十分重要的。
For Sahaja Yogis it is very important to be educated that way
霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須這樣自我教育，
because tomorrow you'll have to talk to other people
因為將來你們要和別人交談，
and you'll have to tell them about Athena, about your traditions,
你們要向他們談論有關雅典娜，有關你們的傳統、背景，
about your background and how it is connected to Sahaja Yoga,
以及它們如何與霎哈嘉瑜伽聯繫起來；
connected to Mother Mary, connected to Christ and all those things.
如何與聖母瑪利亞、基督等等各樣事物聯繫起來。
For this, it is very necessary that we all should try to understand
為此，我們所有人都應嘗試瞭解
the historical background of this country
這個國家的歷史背景，
and educate yourself in a way that you can talk about Sahaja Yoga.
進行這樣的自我教育，以便能談論霎哈嘉瑜伽。
As it is, you know, Athena has the Kundalini in Her hand
你們都知道，雅典娜手執昆達裡尼( Kundalini)，
and you can see that clearly that She was the Adi Shakti.
可以淸楚看出，她就是 Adi Shakti(太初母性力量)。
Actually, in Sanskrit language atha means primordial.
事實上，梵文中Atha就是「太初」之意。
So She was the Primordial Mother.
故此她就是太初之母。
Because there was no connection
因為希臘人與印度人
left between the Greeks and the Indians,
的聯繫已經盡失，
this, I mean, translation
我是指，這個翻譯就失傳了，
was not there and they didn't know what it meant by Athena.
世人就無法明白「雅典娜」的字義是什麼。
But Indians know that it is this is the place
但印度人知道，
for the manifestation of the Adi Shakti
這地方是 Adi Shakti(太初之母)顯現之處，
because in the Devi Mahatmyam, if you read, or you will find out
因為在《Devi Mahatmyam》(女神頌)一書中，如果你有讀過，
they have described Greece as the Manipurndwip.
希臘是被形容為 Manipurdwip的，
Means the island in the Manipur. Manipur is this Nabhi Chakra.
意即「位於Manipura之島」。Manipura就是臍輪。
So in the Nabhi there's an island where it is your Greece,
故此在臍輪之處有個島，即希臘所在之處，
where the Goddess resides. Manipur chakra is where She resides.
是女神的居所。Manipura輪穴就是她的居所。
And so, this Athena has been described,
所以，人們就是這樣描述過雅典娜。
and when I went to Her temple I found that there was
當我到訪她的神廟，我發現那兒
a little temple for the child God. That was Shri Ganesha.
還有個「子神」的小廟宇，那就是錫呂‧格涅沙(Shri Ganesha)。
And then, when I went to Delphi, also, when I went there
然後我也去了德爾斐，當我去了那兒時，
I was surprised to see, they showed Me a mound and said,
我很驚訝，他們指著一個土墩說，
"This is the Nabhi, navel of the whole universe."
這就是臍輪(Nabhi)，全宇宙的肚臍。"
I said, "That's correct." But when I turned round there
我說：「說得對。」但當我轉身過來，
were lots of vibrations and what I find is a Ganesha statue there.
那兒的生命能量很強，我看到的就是一尊格涅沙的神像。
Then Gregoire came here he took photographs
之後葛雷瓜來到，
and everything and he saw that.
他也看見並拍了照片。
So now you are the Nabhi. You are sitting here in the Nabhi
故此，你們現正坐在臍輪之上。
of the whole universe. So how important is Nabhi?
正坐在整個宇宙的臍輪之上。臍輪有多重要，
You know that very well, that Nabhi Chakra gets spoilt,
你們都很淸楚，一旦臍輪給弄壞了，
the whole life becomes miserable for a human being.
整個人生都會變的愁苦。
So, on the right side of the Nabhi, as you see,
如你所見，臍輪的右邊是肝。
is the liver and because, of course, we had lots of philosophers,
當然從前有很多哲人，
they used to think a lot and they created lots of tragedies,
他們思想太多了，創作了很多悲劇，
you see Greek tragedy's well known, where a marriage system was
希臘式的悲劇是有名的。
little bit challenged, that there was, say, two men,
婚姻制度受到希臘式悲劇少許挑戰，
one woman or maybe two women, one man
好像什麼二男一女，或二女一男的
and never they felt happy with the marriage.
不愉快的婚姻橋段等，
So the left Nabhi was under attack, throughout.
因此臍輪左邊全面地受到侵害。
To have such a tragedy, they wrote so many, I would say,
要搞出這些悲劇，他們寫了
so many dramas and they played them here and so many plays were there
一幕又一幕的男女不潔關係，
showing that there are two men and one woman
什麼的二男一女，
or two women and one man and no relationship
或二女一男情節，
between the husband and wife which was pure.
卻沒有講一下夫妻的純潔關係。
And that was the tragedy.
那就是悲劇。
It's known all over as the Greek tragedy.
就是所謂著名的希臘式悲劇。
It's all imaginary and people, you see,
那全都是虛構出來的。
became very left-sided to begin with. They started thinking,
首先，人們就會變得偏向左邊。就開始想像：
Oh, this life is a misery. It's a tragedy.
「噢，此生畢竟是悲劇，多愁苦呀，
What should we do? Why should we?
有什麼事可做呢？為什麼是我呢？
Why should we try to show that we are happy?
為何要顯出自己愉快呢？
We are very unhappy people.
我們真多苦難啊。」
And all these things started here to begin with.
所有這些事情首先就是這樣開始的。
Then came these your Orthodox Church.
然後是你們那個東正教會(Orthodox Church)出現。
Now this Orthodox Church is another one, which, of course,
這個東正教是另一個，
is really doesn't treat women very well and treats them
他們的確真的不會善待女性，
as if they are all the time unholy. Certain times
只會把女性視為完全沒有神性：
they cannot go to church and they cannot touch people,
他們有些日子女性不能到教堂、
all kinds of nonsensical ideas they had.
不能觸摸其他人之類的各式各樣荒謬事情。
That also made women very left-sided.
那就令女性變得非常偏左脈。
Then, on top of that, all this was happening
在此上面，
with these tragedies and all that.
還加上這些悲劇等等，
Suddenly the economic problem came up and people felt very,
及突如其來的經濟問題，
sort of, disgusted about that.
人們對此感到極為厭惡。
So the left side became very,
因此，這裡的左脈
very prominent here and that is how I think
變得非常非常突出，
many of these left-sided,
那些偏左脈的，
bhootish organizations started here
與亡魂有關的組織就在此開張，
and many gurus came who made you feel miserable.
很多所謂上師的也來了，他們令你們感到悲苦。
But the worst that was done by the Greek Church
但最差的還是希臘東正教
which made you feel so guilty.
會令人感到內疚，
So you became very left-sided.
從而令你走向左邊。
Now this left-sidedness was later on counter-balanced
現今這些偏左脈的質素
by people who started becoming overactive;
又漸受一些過度活躍的人所抗衡，
thinking too much, working too hard and all those things.
他們思考過度，工作過份忙碌之類。
But still, I think that they don't work very hard as they should work.
不過，我仍感到他們工作不夠努力。
They're on the lazy side, the Greeks are.
希臘人是在懶惰的一邊。
They're on the lazy side. Of course, the Sahaja Yogis are not.
當然霎哈嘉瑜伽士就不是如此。
The Sahaja Yogis have worked very hard,
霎哈嘉瑜伽士很努力地工作，
I can see all that very clearly, but otherwise.
我很淸楚看得見，他們是例外。
So, now to bring out Sahaja Yoga
因此之故，要在希臘開展霎哈嘉瑜伽，
in Greece, is important, first of all, to know
最重要的，首先是
what is our historical background.
瞭解自己的歷史背景。
The second, they should be very well equipped
第二，就是要好好地瞭解輪穴(chakras)，
with the knowledge of chakras and centers
要以如何改善各能量中心的
and how to improve these centers. If you do not have that knowledge,
知識來裝備自己。假若你沒有這些知識，
you cannot face people. It's not that only men should know,
你就不能面對群眾。不單是男人，
women also should know everything about it.
女人也應知道輪穴的一切知識，
What is the chakras are, how they work out
什麼是輪穴，如何運作，
and what are their results are, how do we suffer
有何作用，當輪穴運作受危害時
because our chakras are in danger.
我們如何受苦等等。
All this knowledge is free to you.
所有這些知識都是免費的。
You don't have to pay for this knowledge. Only thing,
你不必為這些知識付款。
every day-to-day life, when you start working out Sahaja Yoga,
在日常生活中，當你開始努力練習霎哈嘉瑜伽，
then you'll find that what I'm saying is absolutely tangible.
就會發現我所說的是絕對實在可觸摸的。
You can verify it. It is so. It's not something in the air.
你可以驗證它。那的確如此。它並非什麼空中樓閣。
It is absolutely there. We can prove everything
它確確實實存在。
that we believe in and we can show others also
我們可以證明一切我們所相信的，
that this is the truth. Is an absolute truth.
並向人顯示這確實是真理，絕對的真理。
We are not here to spread some sort
我們不是要傳播
of a fanaticism or racialism or anything like that,
什麼宗教狂熱主義和種族主義之類的東西，
but we are here to combine the whole world together
而是要以世人同屬一個宇宙，
under one understanding; that we belong to one universe
同一普世信仰的信念基礎上
and we have one universal religion.
把全世界結合起來。
Now, people will ask you then,
人們會問：「那麼
"Have we to give up your religion?"
我們是否要放棄原有的信仰呢？」
You don't have to tell them that you have to give up your religion,
你們不必告訴人須要放棄自己的宗教。
don't have to say that. You don't have to be hard with them at all.
不應那樣說，你們不可嚴詞厲色。
On the contrary, no, no, no, nothing has to be done.
正好相反。「不！不！不！什麼也不必做。
You just come and take to Sahaja Yoga and take to your spirit.
只需要來練習霎哈嘉瑜伽，接受自己的靈體，
Gradually it will start opening out.
慢慢地事情自會顯現出來。」
It has happened with all of you
這個在你們身上全都是如此發生了。
that first when you came to Sahaja Yoga
比較初來霎哈嘉瑜伽，
you were in a different shape. Now gradually,
你們全都判若兩人，漸漸地，
you started opening out, you matured
你開始開放自己，慢慢成長，
and you understood Sahaja Yoga very well.
也瞭解霎哈嘉瑜伽多了。
In the same way, you must teach others in the same manner,
同樣地，你們也必須如此以體諒、
with the same understanding, compassion and love.
愛心和關懷來教導他人。
Otherwise, normally people think that somebody
否則，普通人
is to be condemned all the time.
以為總有人要被指責。
Of course, some are people who are under bad influence
當然有些人曾受過很壞的影響，
and you cannot get along with them, but most of you
令你們難以忍受，但你們大都應該
should know that we have to get more people into Sahaja Yoga
瞭解到要以愛心慈悲和很多的
through our compassion, love and also lot of understanding
關懷體諒來引領更多人來到霎哈嘉瑜伽。
about others' feelings. I've found that even countries
我發覺即使那些霎哈嘉瑜伽
where have been Sahaja Yoga for so many time,
已發展多時的國家，
suddenly someone comes up and starts giving trouble
仍然有可能突然有人會帶來麻煩、
and becoming bhootish sort of thing, you see, and misbehaving.
被亡魂所附、或言行失去分寸等等。
Suddenly, it happens. Such a person, you know, if it is informed,
是會突然發生的。這種人，假如及早瞭解，
we can take him out of Sahaja Yoga. We can cleanse him.
我們便能把他淸除出霎哈嘉瑜伽。我們可以潔淨他。
But all of you must know one thing for definite
但你們必須淸清楚楚瞭解，
that you all have these powers to cure yourself,
自己有多大力量去醫治自己、
improve yourself, to help others.
改善自己、幫助別人；
You can do everything yourself.
你們可自行成就一切事情。
You all have these powers, but the only thing
你們擁有一切這些力量。不過，
is you have to be sincere and honest.
條件是你得要誠懇和誠實；
If you are not sincere and honest, it will never work out.
假如你不誠懇誠實，事情就永不會成就。
On the contrary, it will boomerang on you.
相反，它會回頭反擊。
So, in Sahaja Yoga, it's very impor- tant is the sincerity of purpose.
所以，在霎哈嘉瑜伽，誠摯的目的是十分重要的。
You must have complete sincerity of purpose
你必須有完全誠摯的目的，
that you are here to achieve your own self-emancipation, first.
明白自己存在的首要目標是達到真我的解放。
And secondly, you are here to help others.
其次，你存在的目的是要幫助別人。
The people all along in the whole world now require help.
全世界各處現在都有人需要幫助，
There's so many problems, so many catastrophes,
問題、災禍和可怕的事情如此多，
so many horrible things we everyday know going on.
每天我們都知道它們在發生。
So now we need people who are solid, who are balanced,
所以，今天我們需要那些紮實的、平衡的、
who are peaceful, who understand what is right and what is wrong.
平和的和那些能明白對錯的人。
But apart from that, you should know
不單如此，你們還要明白
that you have now entered into the Kingdom of God.
自己已經進入了上帝的國。
Many people will say, all right, we were so religious,
很多人會說：「好吧！我們這般虔誠，
we were praying to Christ, we were praying to this one,
對基督敬拜，對這個對那個常敬拜，
praying to that one. What did we get?
得著什麼呢？」
You cannot get it because you are not connected.
你不能得著什麼，因為你沒有連接上。
You have to be connected. Once you are connected to that,
你必須要有連接。一旦與那大能連接上，
then you will find that things start sorting out.
就會發覺事情會順利地成就。
But sincerity is very important and faith in yourself.
誠懇是十分重要的，對自己的信念也是十分重要的。
You must have faith in yourself that you're quite capable,
你必須內裡有信念，相信自己有很大的能力，
quite capable person and you can achieve
是能力高的人，可以達至
a very high degree of awareness by which you can work out many things.
非常高層次的意識，從而成就很多事情。
It doesn't matter from what sort of background you come in.
你的背景和出身不重要，
of country you come in,
你的國籍或種族等等
race anything.
都不重要，
You all can do very well
你們可以做得很好。
and we have seen this happening in so many countries where we had
我見過在很多原本看來毫無希望的國家，
no hope at all. For example, a country like Russia,
都發生過。例如像俄羅斯這樣的國家，
imagine, they've never worshipped any God.
試想像，他們之前從不敬拜神，
They didn't know about God. They were not allowed to know
不懂什麼叫做神。他們不允許
about any religion, anything,
去認識宗教，或之類，
but suddenly I went there, I don't know, they recognized Me, suddenly.
但突然間，我到訪當地，不知怎的他們就是這樣認出我，
They just recognized Me and just with My photograph
突然的。就單是憑我的照片就認出了我，
I find them there. I was amazed that the first time
就有大批人來，真令人驚歎。
I went to Leningrad there were two thousand seats in the hall,
我首次到列寧格勒時，禮堂原有二千座位，
but outside they were all standing. I said,
但外邊仍站滿了人。我問他們：
"Why are they standing outside?" They said,
「為何有這麼多人站在外面呢？」他們說：
"All the seats are full, Mother, and these are extra people.
「母親，裡面已滿座了，其餘的人只好站著等，
There are more than two thousand outside." So I said,
有超過二千人在外面。」我說：
"This is too much." And so they said, "Mother, what about us?"
「真太多人了！」他們說：「母親，我們該怎麼辦呢？」
I said, "All right, let me finish the program."
我說：「好吧，讓我先完成這次講座。」
I went inside, did the program, everything happened
我進去做講座，對發生的一切，
and you'll be amazed
你們會很驚歎，
when we had the program, the people who were outside
他們一直仍在外面等。
were still waiting. I gave realization to people
講座中我給人自覺，
and they were waiting, waiting, waiting.
他們仍在等啊等。
When I came out I gave them.
出來時
I said, "Now, what to do?
我說現在怎麼辦好呢，
I can't give you realization just now."
不能就此給他們自覺吧。
So they said, "All right, what can we do?"
他們問：「那麼怎麼辦好呢？」
I said, "Tomorrow morning can you come?" They said,
我說：「你們可以明天早上來嗎？」。他們說：
"All right." So all those who were inside and those who were outside,
「好的。」就這樣原本在裡面和外面的人
all of them came and came and sat down
都一同來了。
and that open ground and I gave them realization.
他們坐在外面空地上，我都給他們自覺了。
So this is the first beginning, but now in Moscow
這只是個開端，現今在莫斯科
or any place we have to reserve a huge, big stadium.
或其他地方，我們要預訂一個大球場，
Fourteen to sixteen thousand people are there
令四萬至六萬人
and realization is being given.
可得自覺。
But they are so quick to accept Sahaja Yoga,
他們是如此快速地接受霎哈嘉瑜伽，
so quick to accept Me, so quick to understand Sahaja Yoga.
如此快速地接受我，很快就明白霎哈嘉瑜伽。
I just can't imagine how these Russians have got this capacity.
我真難想像這些俄國人何來這般能耐。
No question of their going back,
他們的回歸不容置疑，
no question of their sincerity being challenged.
他們的熱誠不容置疑，
There is no question of their doubting themselves, nothing.
他們也不懷疑自己。
Just there and so much so, so much that I sometimes feel
一切都發生了。如是者有時
this democracy has just harmed us.
我感到民主政治反害了我們。
Because of democracy,of course, we could do Sahaja Yoga all right,
雖然民主政治令我們可以自由地搞霎哈嘉瑜伽。
but where the people are, absolutely sometimes very idiotic.
但它有時真的令人變得十分愚笨。
Like in America, I find there's very idiotic people live there
例如美國人就很愚昧。
and they were only busy choosing their bathrooms
他們只會忙於挑選浴室、
and their curtains and their soaps and all the time they will choose,
窗簾和肥皂，整天忙於挑選
only busy with all these nonsensical things.
所有這些荒謬的東西；
They are so idiotic, while the people in Russia are so sensible,
他們如此稭猜，但相比之下，俄國人就明智得多，
so deep, so introspective and even the artists and the scientists.
有深度、且懂得內省，即使藝術家和科學家也如是。
I had a conference with the scientists. There were about three hundred of them
有一次，在300位科學家出席的會議中，
and I started talking to them about science.
我想最好先和他們講講科學，
I thought, better start with science.
當我開始同他們講科學時，
They said, "Mother, no more science, no more science.
他們就說：「母親，請不要再提科學了。
Tell us the science of God."
請告訴我們上帝的科學。」
Such open-minded people.
這是多麼思想開放的人呢。
We have two hundred doctors in Russia
在俄國我們有200位醫生
who are practicing Sahaja Yoga and it has spread up to Siberia.
在練習霎哈嘉瑜伽，傳揚遠至西伯利亞。
Now, what's the use of this democracy
現在這些不能把人帶到上帝那裡的
which doesn't take us to God. It doesn't give us sense
民主政治又有何用呢；
that we should seek God and we should be humble towards God.
它不能給你找尋上帝所需的智慧，我們必須對上帝謙卑。
So what's the use of having this kind of a democracy and
這類民主和自由有何用呢？
this kind of freedom which has made us mad and idiotic?
它們只令人瘋癲和愚昧。
And that's very true about every democratic country
對每一個民主國家來說此話放諸四海皆准，
because you must know democracy is money-oriented.
因為如你們所知，民主政治是向錢看的。
And you know Greeks are very money -oriented people also, as well.
希臘人也是十分向錢看的，
Of course, they're not as bad as Americans,
當然不及美國人般瘋狂，
but they are quite money-oriented.
但仍是很看重錢財。
Also, Italians are very money-oriented,
義大利人也如是，
but the worst is the corruption.
但最壞的就算是貪污腐敗。
Now Italy is getting exposed.
現在義大利給揭露了，
I'm sure your country will also get exposed.
我肯定你們的國家也會給揭露出來，
All these countries are to be exposed.
所有這些國家也會給揭露出來。
But, first of all, the Sahaja Yogis have to be firm people.
但首先霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須是堅定的人，
They have to be very, very firm and they should know that
十分堅定的人。人們要知道
Sahaja Yoga is only spirit-oriented,
霎哈嘉瑜伽是靈性取向的，
nothing but
不是其他，只重靈性。
that you have to have your spirit enlightened,
你必須讓靈體得到啟發，
that your spirit has to work everything,
讓你的靈體來成就一切。
that you are not this body, this money, this position,
因為你不是這個身體、這金錢、這地位、
these powers, nothing. But you are the spirit.
這些權力等等，不是什麼，而是真真正正是靈。
This is what one has to know.
這是人要清楚明白的事情。
I was told it is very difficult for you
我知道對你們來說
to come for pujas to Cabella
參加義大利卡貝拉的崇拜很難。
you all cannot join, but one week,
或許你們可騰出一星期
supposing you take during Guru Puja, I think.
來參加導師崇拜吧。
You can come by boat or something like that,
你們可坐船來到熱拿亞，
and then we can organize your coming down.
然後大家會為你們安排交通。
For Guru Puja, you all should come. You see, Sahasrara Puja
你們都應該來導師崇拜，
and Guru Puja are very important
頂輪崇拜與導師崇拜都很重要，
and if you could come for Guru Puja, it would be a very nice idea.
如果你們能來導師崇拜，真是個好主意。
I think it can be arranged and organized
我想你們來導師崇拜
that you can come to Guru Puja.
是不難安排的。
I know it's wherever I am,
我知道，無論我在哪，
supposing if I have it here, then for all the rest of the people
假如崇拜在這兒做，對世界各地很多人來說
it will be far away. So I just thought of Milan
會遠了一點；故此我想米蘭地區
being quite in the center that it would be nearer to England,
算是在中心點，對英格蘭
nearer to other European countries.
和很多歐洲城市來說都很近。
You see, the Americans and the South Americans
對美國和南美洲人來說
find it very difficult, so this time
卻不太方便，故此這次
we had to provide all tickets, everything
我們為南美洲人提供了機票等。
to South Americans to come. But they're very deep people.
但他們很有深度，
I was surprised in Colombia, they are such good Sahaja Yogis,
我在哥倫比亞時很驚訝，他們是如此優秀的霎哈嘉瑜伽士，
very beautiful Sahaja Yogis.
美好的霎哈嘉瑜伽士，
Very simple-hearted, very good, well educated.
十分單純，有教養。
Three, four of them got married in India and they're very happy.
有三、四個剛在印度成了親，他們十分開心。
So, now for that, two things have to be done.
有兩件事你們應當做。
Firstly, is that you should come to collective.
首先，每個人都應來到集體，
It's very important. You all should come to collective
這是非常重要的。你們所有人都應來到集體，
and put your - please put attention to Me, not to them, alright.
請把注意力放在我身上，不是他們。
Please put your attention towards Me,
請把注意力放在我身上，
don't turn your attention very much.
不要把注意力搖擺分散，
You have to keep your attention all right. It's very important.
你必須好好看顧自己的注意力。那是非常重要的。
So you have to one thing is to do, is to come to the collective
所以首先要做的是要來到集體，
and watch out for your attention. Where is your attention?
且小心看顧自己的注意力。自己的注意力在哪兒？
Where are you looking? Are you turning your head too much
自己在看什麼呢？是否左顧右盼太多？
or are you putting your attention straight?
還是目不斜視？
It's very important that you must keep your attention
要保持注意力絕對全神貫注，
absolutely wrapped and towards the meetings
放在這一刻你為集體而來的
that you have here for your collective.
聚會之上，那是十分重要的。
In that way, when your attention is fixed you'll find
那樣，你的注意力會固定下來，
you'll definitely rise into thoughtless awareness,
你會發現自己將絕對地升至無思慮的覺醒狀態、
a state where you grow spiritually.
一種在靈性上成長的狀態。
where you grow spiritually.
那是在靈性上成長的狀態。
If you're not in thoughtless awareness,
人若不在無思慮的覺醒狀態
you cannot grow in your spirituality.
就不能在靈性上成長。
So it's very important to see where is your attention.
因此看顧自己的注意力非常重要。
Where are you putting your attention?
你把注意力放在什麼地方呢？
If the attention could be controlled
假如注意力得到控制，
then things will be all right.
事情便能順利完成。
He is crying, the child is crying,
這孩子在哭，
may be you can take him outside a litle bit,
可帶他出去一會，
he is feeling hot I think is all right now with the mother
可能是感到熱了一點吧。有媽媽在，會沒事的。
So the first thing is to be in the collective.
所以第一件事就是融入集體。
Now it's a very sinister, also idea of some people
現在情況凶險，而且有些人
is to always break the collective, to create problems,
會圖謀分化集體，製造麻煩，
to disregard the leaders. As a result, leaders also get so fed up,
蔑視領袖。因而令領袖們煩厭得
they give up, you see. They don't want to have anything to do.
要放棄。他們不想做事，
So they put up their own ideas, they try to trouble the leaders,
只想自以為是，
they create problems for them, they just try to show off everywhere,
為領袖製造麻煩，到處炫耀，
as if they know everything. All such people also create groups.
好像什麼都懂。所有這類人都會搞小圈子，
So beware about them. You should stick on always to the collective
要當心。你們必須經常凝聚在集體之中，
and not to anyone who tries to create a kind of a group at all
而不是在那些總愛製造麻煩，
or who troubles or who makes things difficult.
令事情難以推進的小圈子中。
You must understand those who are collective only will grow,
必須明白，只有那些合群的人才會成長，
those who aren't, will not grow. Because like a nail, if it breaks,
不合群就不會。好像指甲一旦被剪下，
then it doesn't grow. In the same manner,
它就不會再生長一樣；
if you keep out of this thing, by any chance,
假如你能遠離這東西，
if you have any problems with the leaders,
假如你們跟領袖發生什麼問題，
you can always write to Me,
可寫信告訴我，
you can tell Me, I can work it out.
我自會解決。
But all the time, to go on like this and grouping
必須經常提防
like this will break and there will be someone who'll do that.
這類製造分化的人，
There will be some negative person who'll try to do that.
總會有些負面思想的人出來搞這種事。
So, you have to be very careful not to get out of the collective.
所以必須提醒自己不要離開集體；
You must always support the collective,
必須常常支持集體，
must help this collective and must nourish it.
幫助集體，滋養它。
As you know, I was telling him also
你們知道我告訴過他，
that he, if he has problem with money,
假如經濟上有困難，
we can give money from Cabella
我們可從卡貝拉撥錢過來。
because before that I used to travel on My own.
從前我一向自付旅費，
Even to Greece, I came on My own, and paid for everything.
到希臘來也如是，自付一切費用。
So, see also, then Stomatis had to pay something,
但Stomatis說要分擔一些，
which I didn't like very much. He was paying so much,
雖然我不太喜歡。他付了這麼多，
because we had such a small group.
當時集體比較小。
But now as you have a big group, you feel responsible,
不過，現在集體壯大了，
you want to pay for it. All right, doesn't matter.
你們感到有此責任要負擔經費，那可以的；
But not to pay for your Sahaja Yoga, not for your realization,
不過，不要以為是為了霎哈嘉瑜伽而付費，為得到自覺，
not for knowledge of Sahaja Yoga. This is there.
得到霎哈嘉瑜伽的知識而付費。它就是等你來取用。
And so people will start putting ideas into your heads that,
有些人就是這樣開始把怪念頭塞給你，
Why this? Why that?", and all that.
為什麼這樣？為什麼那樣？
Such people you should keep out because you are here
應遠離這類人。你們到來
to develop your spirituality and not to listen
是為了發展靈性，不要聽這些
to these stupid people who have been troublesome.
不時製造麻煩的蠢人的話。
So best is to keep to your own,
最好就是專注於自己的發展，
own development and own nourishment. It's very important.
如何培育自己，那是十分重要的。
So it is in a way collective, but also individual,
故此那某方面既是群體的事，也是自己的事，
because what you're gaining out of the collective
因為你應留心看看自己從集體中
you should be on the watch out, you should see for yourself
得到了什麼。你應看看自己
what you are gaining out of the collective.
從集體中獲得什麼。
Then secondly, at home, you must every day, every day,
另一點就是：在家裡，你必須，每天，每天，
every day, again I say, not to miss it out,
每天，我再重覆一遍，不要忘記做，
in the evening before sleeping you must have meditation.
晚上睡前一定要靜坐。
You can wash yourself up, like,
你可以清洗自己，
what you call, the water treatment or anything
即是你們所稱的「水療法」或什麼的，
then sit down for meditation for ten minutes.
然後坐下來靜坐10分鐘。
You must give fifteen minutes to yourself and then sleep off.
你必須給自己留下15分鐘，才去睡覺。
Supposing you can't do one night, doesn't matter,
假如有一晚不能做，不要緊。
but try to do it every night. If not possible,
一晚做不成，但要嘗試每晚都做。
if you don't do it one night, you can do it in the morning.
晚上做不成，就在早上做吧。
But it's very important. I can easily make out a person
這是十分重要的。我可以很容易分辨出
who does meditation and who does not do meditation.
誰人有靜坐，誰沒有。
It's a difference, such a difference. I immediately know a person
人的面容會很不同。我可以很容易辨認出
who is meditating everyday, in his health,
誰人每天有靜坐，他的健康、面容、
in his face, in his behavior, in everything, he's very different.
行為，一切都會不同。
And those who do not do any meditation you'll find,
你會發覺那些不靜坐的人
not only that they are funny, but their children are funny,
不但行為滑稽，其子女也滑稽，
their relationships are funny, everything is funny.
親人也滑稽；一切都滑稽。
So the meditation is a very important part for you.
所以靜坐是你生活中非常重要的部分，
Because also the women who are pregnant, when they,
孕婦也一樣。
if they do not meditate their children turn out
假如她們不靜坐，生下的孩子
to be very troublesome and very funny. It's a thing like that.
會令人煩厭，十分滑稽。事情就是這樣，
It effects everything. But your character of meditativeness,
它反映了一切。你們因入靜而來的品格、
your character of Sahaja Yoga helps everyone, your children,
因霎哈嘉瑜伽而來的品格會幫助每一個人，
your family, your society, everybody,
以致你的兒女、家人、社會。
and everybody can make it out what sort of a family you are,
每個人都能看得出你來自怎麼樣的家庭、
what sort of a people you are, what sort of a personality you are.
有怎麼樣的品格。就是由於你們，
And from you they take to Sahaja Yoga.
人家才會接受霎哈嘉瑜伽。
So is important in individual life also just to meditate, nothing else.
故此，每個人的生命當中，只有靜坐才是至為重要的，沒有其他。
You have to come to a state of thoughtless awareness.
你必須到達「無思慮的覺醒」狀態，
So the mantra is, as you know, Nirvichara.
你們都知道，囗訣(Mantra)是"Nirvichara"。
You should use the mantra of Nirvichara
你們可以用Nirvichara的口訣來達到
for coming to the state of thoughtlessness
「無思慮的覺醒」狀態，
and try to increase this area,
也要嘗試擴展這個範圍，
this space of thoughtless awareness
這「無思慮的覺醒」狀態的空間。
and that is how you will find you will be growing very much.
這就是你們發現自己會大大成長的方法。
Now as you get lots of powers, as you get lots of people
現在你們已擁有很多力量，
being realized by you, curing by you,
令很多人得到了自覺，醫治了他們，
sometimes maybe it might affect your ego.
就有可能會引來自我膨脹的問題。
You might get into ego things. For such people, I have to say
得了自我(ego)的種種東西。我的忠告是
that you have to be introspective and see for yourself.
多內省，向內裡看看。
You face the mirror and ask now how much ego you have.
並向著鏡子自問現在我的自我有多大。
Laugh at yourself. Once you start laughing at yourself,
要嘲笑自己。一旦開始自嘲，
your ego will drop out and you'll understand
便能丟棄自我，並會明白
that it was false to have this kind of ego within you.
內裡擁有這種自我是錯誤的事。
There are so many ways and methods of finding out about yourself.
有很多方法可以找出自己的問題。
Put yourself into bandhan and put your hands towards the photograph,
先做班丹，手朝向相片。
immediately you can feel what chakras are catching
你會立刻感到有什麼輪穴被感染，
and you know how to clear it out. Also sometimes you feel it inside.
你會懂得如何潔淨它。有時是在裡面感應到的。
If your chakras are catching, you can feel it inside
假如你有輪穴感染，你在內裡能夠感應到它，
and you can feel it, the different centers
也在指尖上感應到不同的
on your fingertips about yourself.
能量中心來瞭解自己。
So it is about yourself you will know. About others, you know,
這樣便會瞭解自己，瞭解有關別人的事，
you should just talk on chakras. You should not say,
你們應該只談輪穴。你不應說：
he's bhootish, or he has ego - nothing. But you should say,
「他是亡魂附體。」或「他很自我」之類。不要這樣說。
his Agnya is catching, means he has got ego.
你應說他的額輪受感染。那意味著他有「自我」。
You can say, his Nabhi's bad, his, this thing is bad.
又或可說他的臍輪不好，什麼不好等等。
So the language is to change now.
故此現在語言上要改變一下，
We have to talk in the language of Sahaja Yoga.
必須用霎哈嘉瑜伽的語言來表達。
It is to be understood that now we are Sahaja Yogis.
必須明白今天你們都是霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
We've got the powers we have vibratory powers.
你獲得了大能，有生命能量上的能力，
But if you don't use these vibratory powers, what is going to happen?
但假如你不用這些能量的能力，又會怎樣呢？
We have to use them, that's the point.
我們必須好好利用，那才是重點所在。
We always forget. I've seen, the other day
我們就是常忘記了。前幾天他們
they couldn't open something. I said, "Give a bandhan."
打不開某東西，我說：「做個班丹吧。」
Gave a bandhan and immediately it worked out, you see.
他們一做，問題就立刻解決了。
Small, small things also you'll be surprised
即使是很小很小的不能解決的事情
that if it doesn't work out, you have to just give a bandhan
也可以令人驚訝地用班丹就解決了。
and it works out.
有一點很重要的，
It is important to know that you are Sahaja Yogis,
就是必須知道你們是霎哈嘉瑜伽士，
you are saints and that you can do lots of things
都是個聖人，可以成就很多事情。
and you shouldn't forget it. You shouldn't forget it
這些是你不應忘記的。不要忘記
that you are Sahaja Yogis. Now you are no more ordinary people.
你們是霎哈嘉瑜伽士，你們已不再是普通人，
You are saints now and you can do a lot.
你們是聖人，可以成就很多事情。
All this, when it works out, you'll be amazed at yourself how,
當所有這些都得以成就，你會驚歎自己，
how you have achieved all these things.
驚訝如何成就所有這些事情。
And, I tell you, people tell Me that they look like roses,
我告訴你，有人告訴過我這些人像玫瑰一樣的，
all of their faces shining, they look so beautiful and
全都面容光亮，漂亮極了。
they can make it out that you are Sahaja Yogis.
他們可認得出這些是霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
I've seen at the airport also many people say that,
我見到那天在機場也有人問：
"Who were those people
「這些人是誰，
looking so sweet and beautiful, shining. Who were those?"
個個儀容甜美，面帶光采？他們是誰？」
So if I tell them that they are saints, they won't believe
假如我告訴他們這些人是聖人，他們不會相信
that there could be so many saints, but there are
世上可以有這麼多聖人。但事實上
and we have achieved that all over the world.
確實如此，且在世界各地都達成了。
All over the world now there are so many Sahaja Yogis
現今世界各地已有這麼多霎哈嘉瑜伽士，
that I can't even say how many they are, in thousands and thousands.
連我也無法計算，成千上萬的。
So, I again tell you that Greece
故此我要告訴你們，
is a place where you can do a lot.
希臘是個你們可以做很多事情的地方。
First of all, you must establish yourself in Sahaja Yoga
首先，你要好好地在霎哈嘉瑜伽之內鞏固自己，
and you have to know what you are,
並知道自己是誰，
all the time to remember what you are. You are a Sahaja Yogi.
常常記住自己是誰，你是個霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
Even to children, you have to say, "You are a Sahaja Yogi,"
就算是小孩，你也應對他們說：「你是霎哈嘉瑜伽士。」
so they also develop that personality by which
他們就可以發展出應有的品格，
they behave properly and they behave in a manner
一個霎哈嘉瑜伽士
that a Sahaja Yogi should behave.
應有的端正言行。
So all these things are just the preliminaries of Sahaja Yoga,
這些都是霎哈嘉瑜伽之中最根本的東西。
but I am sure you must be getting my tapes from Cabella
但我肯定，你們都從卡貝拉收到我的錄影帶，
and you must be knowing about all the deeper things
且一定知道很多有關自己
about yourself and about Sahaja Yoga.
和霎哈嘉瑜伽較深層的事。
It's a new age that has started.
一個新時代已經開始了，
The other day I said that the Satya Yuga has started now.
前幾天我說過 Satya Yuga(完滿期)現在已經開始了。
So it will start exposing all that is a-satya,
它會開始揭露所有非真理(Asatya)的事物，
which is whatever is false. All those who are false people
所有虛假的東西。所有那些假導師
will be exposed and you'll be amazed at the way
都會被揭露出來。你們會驚訝
things will work out. And it's such a great time you are born
事情如何成就出來。你們生於這個何等偉大的時代，
and it's such a great thing that you have come to Sahaja Yoga
能夠來到霎哈嘉瑜伽是何等的大事，
and that you have got your realization
能夠獲得自覺，
and that you are one of those
並且成為一同把整個宇宙的
who have to lift the whole of this universe into a higher awareness.
意識一起提升的一員。
Of course, we can't say how many will be saved.
當然，我們不能說有多少人得救。
It's another point because what I know about is that
那是另一回事，
in the evolutionary portion, supposing we came from chimpanzees,
在進化過程中，可能我們是來自猩猩，
many were lost in between, you know,
中間有很多人迷失，
and there are so many chimpanzees now left
故此現在仍剩下這麼多猩猩，
and there's the middle, the people were lost.
而在過程中人們迷失了。
In the same way, many human beings may be lost
同樣，很多人會因為自身的愚昧，
because of their stupidity, because of their self-destructive habits
一些已經形成的自毀的習性，
that they have formed.
就會迷失。
But your responsibility is very great.
但你們的責任很大呢。
Don't think, I am just mediocre. I'm good for nothing.
不要以為「我是平庸之材，我一無是處。」
Never. Never think like that.
決不要這樣想。永遠不要這樣想。
You are all saints and you are capable of great things.
你們都是聖人，有能力成就大事
May God bless you.
願神祝福你們。
So today they want to do the puja of Athena
今天你們想做一次雅典娜的崇拜，
And you will be surprised that the names of Athena
你們會驚訝雅典娜的名字
are exactly about the same as that of the Goddess, of Adi Shakti.
與女神 Adi Shakti[太初母性力量亅的意思是一模一樣的。
Is very surprising, they have such beautiful names.
這個美麗的名號真令人驚歎。
But we can have hundred and eight names of… today
但我們今天可念誦108個名號。
and you can read the names and the meanings
你們可念誦名號及讀出意思，
and they can say the mantras.
他們可誦出囗訣(Mantra)。
But first the children have to wash My feet
首先，讓孩子們為我沐足，
with Ganesha stuti, you can sing
其他人可唱
Ganesha stuti.
Ganesha stuti.
You've got some musical instrument or not?
你們有些樂器嗎？
Yes, yes. You have.
好！